Previously on
Falling Skies...
This alliance
that you've created
with this new set of aliens --
is a load of crap.
They have given us no cause
to doubt their loyalty.
What is
going on with you?!
I've been
going to see Karen.
She implanted something
in me.
I don't think
she's human.
What are you doing here?
I work for the real President,
Benjamin Hathaway.
If Benjamin Hathaway
is alive,
we don't know
where he is.
The Espheni are coming.
We're all gonna die.
Hey, let me fight!
♪ Falling Skies 3x05 ♪
Search and Recover
Original Air Date on June 30, 2013
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
What's going on?
I don't know.
What's up?
- It's Anne and Alexis.
- What about them?
They're missing.
Dr. Glass asked me
to analyze the DNA
of 12 de-harnessed children.
11 presented with no
abnormalities whatsoever.
But one showed signs
of alien DNA,
the strands intertwining
with human DNA
like kudzu in
a Northwestern rainforest.
It's a vine-like plant
in the genus pueraria --
Doctor, please.
The point.
The baby...Is not human.
So...she's an alien?
No, she's a hybrid,
a-an entirely new species.
At least, that's
my preliminary analysis.
After Dr. Glass
left Dr. Kadar,
she went back to her room,
drugged Lourdes,
and, as far as we can tell,
she took Alexis,
but we don't know where.
We were having
a glass of wine,
and...the --
the next thing I knew,
C-Colonel Weaver
was shaking me awake.
So...
she just disappeared?
Seems that way.
And they're not
in Charleston anywhere?
We've searched everywhere.
Dr. Glass wouldn't just
run away. That's not like her.
It's possible
she was afraid
what would happen if people
found out about the baby.
I think she just did
what any mother would do.
I agree -- Anne is not
the type of person
who goes around knocking people
out or -- or drugging them.
Colonel,
if she's in the badlands --
we're gonna need a search party.
Won't need more than 50,
maybe 100 volunteers.
Colonel.
Travel by horseback --
cover more ground that way.
Colonel Weaver!
Ms. Peralta.
A moment, please.
I need you to get
some perspective here.
On what, Ms. Peralta?
You know we can't afford
100 people for a search party.
We can't afford 50 people
or 20 people.
We can't afford anyone.
We're talking about Anne Glass
and her newborn daughter,
Tom Mason's newborn daughter.
I understand that.
I'm not sure you do.
I most certainly do,
but there are 5,000 other lives
that I have to consider.
Now, if you want to go
look for her,
and I assume you do,
you have my blessing.
I can't conduct an effective
search by myself.
- You know that.
- I'm sorry.
It's my final decision.
Ms. Peralta,
when Tom left you in charge,
I don't think
that he counted on --
Counted on what,
Colonel?
Looking out for the best
interest of Charleston?
Because I believe
that's exactly
what he was counting on from me,
and from you, as well.
Ms. Peralta.
I can't expect you
to understand
what we in the 2nd Mass
went through,
but we came out
of it a family,
a family dedicated
to each other, come what may.
And that's what the 2nd Mass
has come to stand for.
That's what we've been
fighting for.
And if one of us is lost,
we find them,
and if one of us
is in trouble, we help them.
Fine. 24 hours.
All right, then.
And if you do find them,
we'll need to figure out a way
how to handle the baby.
What do you mean, "handle"?
Dr. Glass was right.
God knows how people will react
to a hybrid child.
First things first.
Yes, first things first.
And by the way...
I had a family, too...
Once.
I completely understand
what we're fighting for --
completely.
What happened?
We crashed.
Bressler?
Dead.
You pulled me
out of that thing?
Didn't take them long
to find us.
Or Keystone
for that matter.
Yeah, well, considering the fact
that you led them
right to it, I'm surprised it
took them as long as it did.
Could have let you burn
on that plane.
Charleston has a mole.
Everybody knows it.
Only instead of delaying
your trip to Keystone
to find out
who the damn spy was,
you -- you wanted to
go and play
with the big boys,
didn't you?
Parley with the President
of the United States.
Well, I hope
it was worth it, huh?
You get the President killed,
Bressler's dead.
And I'm out
a damn fine airplane. Geez.
It looks like they're leaving.
We got to move.
No, stay here for a while, all
right? Wait until they leave.
- Suit yourself.
- No! Down!
Stay down!
Listen, if there's
one thing I know,
it's how to hide from
the authorities, all right?
Let's just stay here.
We wait it out until they pass.
You're not
leaving me behind.
Come on, buddy.
It's not safe out there.
I don't care.
Anne and Alexis are just as
important to me as anyone else.
Well, you're not going.
And that's that.
Damn it!
Hey!
Watch your language, son.
Now,
what's going on here?
Hal said that I couldn't go,
but I said --
Of course
you're coming with.
- Sir --
- No buts about it, Hal.
Matt's coming.
That's an order.
He can ride with me.
- I'll make sure nothing happens to him.
- Right.
Let's go.
- Colonel.
- Ms. Peralta.
Listen, I didn't mean
to come across as -- as un--
I got what you were saying,
Ms. Peralta.
What I wanted to say --
I-I wa--
just get yourself back to
Charleston safely, Colonel.
We can't do without you.
She likes you, dad.
Who? Ms. Peralta?
That woman hates me.
- Dad.
- What?
Let's head out!
Let's go.
Which way?
South,
back to Charleston.
How the hell do you know
that south ain't that way?
Moss.
Grows on the north --
less sun.
South.
Very good.
But you also know that
Charleston has got to be, what,
400 miles
as the crow flies?
So, even if we're covering
three miles an hour,
times 10 hours a day,
if we find a road --
actually, they'll be looking for
the road, so we can't even --
Lieutenant Fisher didn't give us
the coordinates till we were airborne.
What?
Spy couldn't have known
where we were going.
He didn't have the coordinates.
We didn't have the coordinates.
He knew we were going.
He didn't need to know where.
Look, Professor, you know
as well as I do, they got --
they got eyes
in the sky, right?
Then why did it take them
so long to get to Keystone?
You are the King of chaos,
Mason.
Do you know that?
It follows you.
Don't try to explain it.
Just own it.
You still owe me
an airplane.
What you got, son?
Blood.
Dismount.
Jeanne, Maggie, Hal,
spread out.
It's still fresh.
Up here!
No!
Matt, stay!
It's not Anne.
Skitters?
Could be.
I'm not sure.
We need to bury her.
We don't even know her.
It doesn't matter.
No, Matt's right.
We can't just leave her here.
Come on, Hal.
Come give us a hand.
Ohh, God.
We should put up here
for the night.
No,
we should keep moving.
Still got a couple hours
of light left. Let's go.
No, we should make a fire.
We need to eat something.
Look, in case
you missed the memo,
fire...Is what
attracts them, see?
We could die of exposure,
starvation,
and then
it wouldn't matter.
Are you going soft, Mason?
It's not that cold.
It will be
when the sun goes down.
Make a fire.
Yeah,
while you do what?
What's the matter, Pope?
You don't know how?
Hey, you know what?
You want your fire
bad enough there,
Mr. Boy Scout,
you make it yourself.
You don't know how,
do you?
How could you
survive this long
without knowing
how to make a fire?
I just got this image
of young Tommy Mason
out there in the wilderness
with his old man.
Huh?
"Behold, my son,
the miracle of fire."
I just got an image...
Of a young Johnny Pope
sitting on his ass
making wisecracks
while the other kids played.
My father wasn't really
the outdoorsman type.
Too busy managing
his stock portfolio, huh?
Owned a hardware store.
Never made it past
the 7th grade.
But he knew his tools.
Well, sounds like my
Norman Rockwell upbringing.
My father was a drunk.
Angry, mean drunk.
There was nothing idyllic
about my childhood.
Except that
maybe I survived it.
It's for the tree.
Think we should
say...something?
All right.
I don't know
who this woman was.
She didn't deserve
to die this way.
And she's in a better place.
Amen.
I'm glad we found her.
Do you think
she had a family?
Yeah. Probably.
Bet she was
a good mother.
Yeah, I'm guessing so.
Probably just...
looking for food for her kids.
Like a good mother
would.
Before all this,
probably would have...
taken her daughter for ice cream
after a volleyball game,
even if
she  lost.
She waited up for her daughter
to come home
from her first date.
Not 'cause she was worried
about her,
but...because
she wanted to hear all about it.
She'll be missed.
But she'll always
be loved.
Right.
Let's get her covered up.
Dr. Kadar?
Roger?
Marina!
I know why you're here.
You do?
And I think I have everything
almost ready.
Wh-- I don't know
what you're talking about.
Uh, testing.
What testing?
Lourdes -- uh,
that is to say, Dr. Delgado,
gave me a list
of all the children
born in the last six months
here in Charleston --
eight to be exact --
including, of course,
Dr. Glass' child.
And then it was just a matter
of comparing the DNA samples.
Doctor, that's
a very important project,
and I'd like
to discuss it further,
but that's not why
I'm here.
All right.
I'm, uh...I'm sorry.
What is it?
This is what the Volm
are building.
Yes.
How did you know?
It's not hard
to figure out.
Where did you
get these photos?
That's not important.
What is important
and what I hope you can tell me
is what this thing
does exactly.
"Exactly"?
From these photos?
Well, you're the only one
I could think of
who could possibly
figure it out.
All right. I'll try.
That's all I can ask.
Marina...
Yes.
...does Tom Mason
know about this?
Yes.
He's the one who asked me
to come here.
Matt.
Not hungry.
You should eat anyway.
Do you think
mom died alone?
Like...that woman?
Um...
I don't know.
I hope not.
You remember the last time
you saw mom?
Yeah.
I...saw her leaving
that morning just...
through the window.
All I could see was the bottom
of her legs
from where I was sitting,
her jeans, pink Nikes
dad got her for that cancer run.
Yeah, I...I remember.
The next time I saw her,
she was lying on the picnic
table in the backyard
after dad had gone
and found her.
One of her shoes
was missing.
I should have gone to look
for that shoe.
We're gonna find her,
right?
Anne, I mean.
We're gonna try.
Hey. Eat.
Thanks.
For what?
For not lying.
Huh? I'll tell you,
a little white wine,
lemon and garlic,
cayenne pepper,
it'd be almost edible.
You much of a cook,
Mason?
No. Rebecca did
most of the cooking.
I used to make breakfast
for the boys...
On Saturdays sometimes.
I liked the smell of bacon
and hash browns in the house.
Hmm. I wasn't much of a cook
when my kids were around.
That's right.
You've got two, right?
A boy and a girl.
Brandon and Tanya.
When was the last time
you saw them?
Oh, right.
It was five years
before the invasion.
Me and, uh -- me and my boy
were working on his minibike.
Had this sweet, little,
old-school Honda
that his uncle gave him.
And, uh, swapping out
the rear sprocket...
Give the kid a little extra
torque, you know?
He's riding down the driveway,
and this jackass...
In a Cadillac --
by that much, man.
Almost just run him
right down, right?
I told this guy before.
So, I throw Brandon
into the truck.
We follow this son of a bitch,
get out to his house.
He gets out of his car.
I tell him, "hey, man, we got
kids playing in the street."
He tells me,
"yeah, well, get a haircut.
Shut your pie hole."
And I popped him.
So he goes down.
And, uh...
I actually --
I started laughing 'cause his --
his, uh -- his head
sounded like a melon...
when it hit the asphalt.
I'll never forget the look
on Brandon's face, though, boy.
Just -- I was just
trying to teach him
how to stand up for yourself,
you know?
That's --
that's all I was doing.
What happened to the guy?
He sue you?
No, he bled out
on the driveway.
He ended up dead.
You know what, Mason?
I was never cut out
for the...the homelife...
homeowner crap.
Just never my thing,
you know?
And prison --
prison was easy.
Prison, I-I understood.
You know,
that other stuff...
I was just gonna take
the first watch.
Whoo-hoo!
I don't know about you,
but I'm getting a little tired
of frog legs.
I thought we'd go epicurean
this morning.
You think that's funny?
Ain't nothing funny
about eating snake, man.
Asshole.
It's a joke, you puss.
Oh, you think
we're friends now?
Share a few campfire stories,
and now we're blood brothers?
Move it, Mason!
Move it!
They're flanking us.
Whoa, whoa.
It was nice knowing you,
Mason.
Get out of the way.
No, no, no.
I saw that movie. No way.
You got a better idea?
No!
You want to die?!
Try that again!
Let's finish it.
Let's finish it!
It's finished.
You win.
Do I want to die?
That's rich.
Mason,
you honestly think...
we're getting out of here
any other way?
Huh?
What?
It's my ankle.
Let's get dry.
How you doing, Jeannie?
I don't know.
What's wrong?
Just wondering
if this is how it all ends.
How what ends?
They can't kill us.
They can't dominate us.
So they just turn us
into them?
Create a new species,
half-human, half-alien?
I don't know.
Dad, you have to
promise me something.
You know if I can,
I will.
Don't let them get me,
okay?
What are you
talking about?
You know.
Please.
I don't want them
to use me for --
just promise me,
no matter what, you won't.
Never, ever.
I promise.
Dismount.
Let's spread out.
See what we can see.
Hey. You okay?
Yeah, I'm fine. Why?
You've just been acting weird
this whole time. That's all.
Look, it's just this doesn't
make a whole lot of sense.
I mean, look. Anne, the baby,
they could be anywhere.
If Anne doesn't
want to be found,
she's smart enough
she's not gonna be found.
We have to try, right?
I guess so, yeah.
Skitter tracks.
Some human prints, too.
Can't tell how many.
They've got her.
We can't be sure, son.
Rebel Skitters, they have spies
in the Espheni system.
If anyone can find Anne
and Lexie, it's them.
If they're still alive.
Listen. Anne and your baby
sister are most certainly alive.
All right?
How can you be sure?
Because if they weren't,
we would have found them.
Now, we don't
give up hope ever.
You don't.
And that's an order.
Yes, sir.
When we get back, we'll talk
to your Skitter friends.
And we're gonna launch
those rebel spies.
Let's mount up
and head home.
Give me the belt.
There had to have been a
tracking device on the airplane.
That's the only
explanation.
What the hell
are you talking about?
That's how they knew
we were at Keystone.
Look, you got to let that go,
Mason.
It doesn't matter
anymore.
It's gonna get tight.
We got to get moving.
Let's go.
Get some weight on it.
Come on. Got it?
Damn it, Mason.
We don't have a choice.
Look, Mason,
we got to go.
You hear me?
We're gonna die out here.
We got to go,
and we got to go now.
Go.
No, no. Come on.
I'm not leaving without you.
That's not gonna happen.
One more time. Come on.
Let's go. Let's do it.
Just go.
You got what you wanted.
You get to walk out
of the woods.
It's not gonna work
that way.
You are gonna
get off your ass,
get dressed,
and we are going to move.
You owe me an airplane.
That's it.
That is the only reason that I
am hauling your ass out of here.
You understand that?
What are you gonna do with an airplane?
You got motorcycles.
You got Humvees.
You can leave Charleston
anytime you want.
Why don't you go?
If I did all that,
I think I'd miss out
on all the fun and adventure.
Oh, man, it must be nice
to be John Pope,
to live life
with no responsibility,
no accountability,
no sense of obligation,
no sense of duty,
no sense of honor,
and no sense of remorse!
That must be nice!
Shut up.
You're a fake!
You're a phony!
You are a coward.
I'm gonna die out here.
You're gonna die out here
because you don't have the balls
to walk out of here
without me!
I don't like that look.
It doesn't add up.
What doesn't add up?
Let's say
you had a toaster
that you wanted me
to power up for you.
Most household appliances use
between 300 and 900 watts.
So that's what I'd provide.
That's all I'd provide.
I wouldn't go to the trouble of
creating a system that gives,
say, 25,000 watts,
which would be enough to run
an electric furnace,
because that would be...
overkill.
So, what about this device
is overkill?
This thing right here
is connected,
like some kind of
massive accumulator.
It's, uh...like
an energy-storage device.
And if this weapon uses
plasma armature...
and I think it does,
then...
It would never
need that much power,
not even by a long shot.
It would be...
It would be overkill.
Exactly.
So, maybe it's not
what we think it is?
Or what the Volm
are telling us it is.
What are the Volm
telling us it is?
I don't know.
You don't know?
Tom Mason didn't ask you
to look into this, did he?
No, he didn't.
And he should have.
He should have
told us all.
Thank you, Doctor.
I assume you won't tell anyone
about this.
I think that would be
for the best.
I do have the DNA results back,
by the way,
if you're interested.
Results?
The DNA results
from the newborns.
And?
They're all negative,
except the Glass child.
That's good.
Yes.
It is, I think.
I think it's very good.
Ahh.
Dad. Dad, you got to get up.
How did you find me?
They're here. We got to go.
Who's here?
We don't have much time.
We have to get up.
Where's Anne?
Where's Lexie?
They need your help. You got to
get up right now! Come on, Dad!
One of you doesn't
go home tonight.
Is it you? Or you?
There's only one thing
on this planet
I can't stand
more than you, Mason.
That's Skitters.
Almost there.
It ain't a Harley,
but it'll do.
There's also enough...
gas in this thing.
It should get us
most of the way home.
The folks that owned this tub
weren't much on...
fine dining...
But, uh...they keep
a good supply of 12 gauge.
Oh, here.
The shocks on this buggy
are crap.
That's for mom.
We never talk
about her anymore.
You notice that?
Yeah.
How come?
I don't know.
Hey. What's wrong?
I don't want to
be alone, Ben.
Like that lady.
I don't want it.
I don't want to be --
die facedown,
buried by some strangers.
Hey. Hey.
Hold it!
Stay where you are!
Don't come any further!
Don't shoot!
It's Tom Mason.
We're coming in.
It's the President.
It's President Mason!
What happened, sir?
We ran out of gas.
How long
have I been out?
Two days.
How long have you been
sitting in here?
Two days.
I lived.
I'm sorry
to disappoint you.
Yeah, look, I just think we
should get our stories straight.
What story would that be?
You saved my ass.
I saved yours.
I'd say
that makes us even.
Well, you know what they say
about a tie.
It's like
kissing your sister.
Hey.
Now, there's a sight
for sore eyes.
I'm happy to be seen.
Pope's filled me in
on what happened.
General Bressler --
I hear that his flying
saved your lives.
It's true.
Any word from Cochise
or the President?
Radio silence.
I assume you've contacted
the Volm.
They're out
looking for him.
Hey. Welcome back.
I got
a little headache, Doc.
Aside from that,
I feel fine.
If it's all the same
to you, gentlemen,
I got a business to run.
Hey, Pope.
Next basket wins.
How are you feeling?
Oh, like I survived
a plane crash.
When can I get
out of here?
Um, not for a couple days,
at least.
You were pretty dehydrated,
and it's gonna be a few days
before you can put any weight
on that ankle.
Dad!
Hey.
Good to see you again,
Dad.
I'm glad you made it.
Yeah,
I'm glad I made it, too.
Where's Anne?
Where's Alexis?
Dan, where's Anne?
There's no easy way
to say this, Tom,
so I'm just going
to say it.
Anne and Alexis
are missing -- gone.
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
www.tvsubtitles.net